What are the things that scare you: snakes, spiders or creepy crawlies?
有哪些事物会让你感到害怕：蛇、蜘蛛，还是那些令人毛骨悚然的小爬虫？
Or maybe you have a fear of heights or visiting the dentist.
又或者你恐高，或是害怕去看牙医？
Although some of us just get scared or a bit nervous about these things, for others it can cause an irrational reaction that can’t be controlled – something we call a phobia.
虽然我们中的一些人只是对这些事物感到害怕或些许紧张，但对另一些人来说，这些事物会引发无法控制的非理性反应——我们将这种反应称为恐惧症。
It occurs when someone develops an exaggerated or unrealistic sense of danger about a situation or object.
当一个人对某一情境或物体产生过度且不切实际的危险感时，恐惧症就会出现。
Sometimes it’s good to be aware of the possible dangers from things.
有时，意识到事物可能存在的危险是一件好事。
Our brain alerts us to the risks that might lie ahead, but then we often rationalise the risks and overcome them.
我们的大脑会提醒我们前方潜在的风险，但随后我们通常会理性分析这些风险并解决它们。
Clinical psychologist Warren Mansell told the BBC: “Our fears are hard-wired into our brains – we don’t need to learn to be afraid of animals like snakes or spiders.”
临床心理学家沃伦·曼塞尔在接受BBC采访时表示：“恐惧是我们大脑中与生俱来的反应——我们无需后天学习，就会对蛇或蜘蛛这类动物感到害怕。”
But phobias are stronger than just fears.
但恐惧症比单纯的恐惧要强烈得多。
Warren says: “An area called the amygdala in the brain is recognising a threat and preparing your body for fight or flight.”
沃伦说：“大脑中一个名为杏仁核的区域会识别威胁，并让身体进入‘战斗或逃跑’的准备状态。”
With a phobia, your breathing gets quicker, your pulse speeds up, you sweat, there’s more glucose in your blood, increasing your energy, and your brain is unable to control these reactions.
当恐惧症发作时，人会呼吸急促、脉搏加快、身体出汗，血液中的葡萄糖含量也会升高以提升能量，而大脑无法控制这些反应。
But where does a phobia come from?
但恐惧症究竟从何而来？
Speaking to the BBC, Lauren Rosenberg, a fear and phobia expert, says: “Phobias usually are a copy behaviour from a higher authority, like a parent or teacher, or something you have learnt from your own experience.”
恐惧与恐惧症研究专家劳伦·罗森伯格在接受BBC采访时表示：“恐惧症通常是从权威者处模仿而来的行为，比如父母或老师，也可能是从自身经历中习得的反应。”
Or a trauma from a past event that comes back to haunt you.
此外，过去某件事带来的心理创伤也可能会卷土重来，让人深受困扰。
There are many different complex phobias some people suffer from, such as agoraphobia – triggered by being away from home, social anxiety disorder – feeling anxious in social situations, and iatrophobia – fear of doctors.
人们会患上的复杂恐惧症种类繁多，比如场所恐惧症——由离家外出引发；社交焦虑症——在社交场合中感到焦虑不安；还有医源性恐惧症——对医生感到恐惧。
But how can they be overcome?
但这些恐惧症该如何克服呢？
Cognitive behavioural therapy is one option, where you gradually get used to whatever it is you fear.
认知行为疗法是一种可行的方法，通过这种疗法，患者可以逐渐适应自己所恐惧的事物。
Lauren Rosenburg says she likes to work with people to clear their subconscious memory and help them breathe.
劳伦·罗森伯格表示，她会帮助患者清理潜意识中的相关记忆，并指导他们进行呼吸调节。
But if you do have a phobia, continually trying to avoid what you’re afraid of is likely to make the situation worse, so it’s a good idea to find help to overcome it.
但如果你确实患有恐惧症，持续回避自己的恐惧对象很可能会让情况变得更糟，因此最好寻求专业帮助来克服它。